Ícaro Goulart Faria Motta França

GENERALIST GAME DEVELOPER

Niterói - RJ, Brazil

□ (+55) 21-99845-4218 | Sicarogoulart@yahoo.com.br | 🏕 icaro56.github.io | 🖸 icaro56 | 🛅 icaro-gfmf

"Learning can be leveraged through positive or negative reinforcements. I prefer the positive ones but the negative reinforcements sometimes teach us great lessons."

Summary_

I am a generalist analyst/programmer in the area of game development, interactive programs, simulators, hybrid applications, and web services. Currently, I have Master's Degree in Computer Science at the Federal Fluminense University (UFF). My research field was Artificial Intelligence with a focus on Reinforcement Learning.

Work Experiences ____

MoonLabs Studio

CLIENT SOFTWARE ENGINEER (HOME OFFICE)

Jun. 2021 - current

Nov. 2013 - Jan. 2017

Belo Horizonte-MG, Brazil Jun. 2010 - Oct. 2013

- · Program and develop the Devikins game
- · Main technologies: Unity, Python, MongoDB

AKOM Studio Rio de Janeiro-RJ, Brazil

GAME PROGRAMMER (HOME OFFICE)

- Mar. 2021 Maio. 2021 • Program and architect codes for mobile game development
- Main technologies: Unity e C#

AddLabs Niterói-RJ, Brazil

RESEARCHER Oct. 2018 - Aug. 2019

- Develop new features and maintain the AddCement software for Cementation Evaluation for oil wells.
- Main technologies: C++, QT & MySql

Visual Virtual Belo Horizonte-MG, Brazil

LATEST ROLE: LEAD SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

- Manage the developer team and create the back-end settings and source code for a ride app called Zumpy v3.
- Develop the web service through the REST API in all Zumpy versions.
- Main technologies: JAVA, JPA, JBOSS, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, AmazonWS, Wildfly, XMPP

Devex Tecnologia e Sistemas S/A

• Develop MineInside, software for managing ore mines' integrated operation.

• Main technologies: C++, QT and Ogre 3D

Visual Virtual Belo Horizonte-MG, Brazil

ANALYST DEVELOPER

INTERN PROGRAMMER Mar. 2009 - Jun. 2010

- · Develop new features to MineInside.
- Integrate physx engine into the Visual Virtual engine.

Digital Game Development Course

Belo Horizonte-MG. Brazil

TEACHER'S ASSISTANT POSITION 2009

• To help students with difficulties in the courses: Computer Graphics, 3D Modeling, and Mathematics for Games.

Education

UFF (Universidade Federal Fluminense)

Niterói-RJ, Brazil

MASTER'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Mar. 2017 - Exp. May. 2019

- · Thesis title: Learning how to play Bomberman with Deep Reinforcement and Imitation Learning
- Research field: Computer Graphics, AI and Games
- · Courses Taken: Artificial Intelligence, Computer Vision, Data Visualization, Machine Learning, Analysis and Synthesis of Algorithms, Computer Systems, Machine Learning for Natural Language Processing, and Oriented Study

PUC-Minas (Pontifícia Universidade Católica de Minas Gerais)

Belo Horizonte-MG, Brazil

TECHNICAL DEGREE IN DIGITAL GAME DEVELOPMENT

Jul. 2007 - Exp. Dec. 2009

· Approved

CEFET-Campos (Centro Federal de Educação Tecnológica de Campos dos Goytacazes)

Campos dos Goytacazes-RJ, Brazil

TECHNICAL SCHOOL IN SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

Feb. 2005 - Exp. Dec. 2006

· Approved

Languages_

English: intermediate **Portuguese:** fluent

Spanish: intermediate

Skills_

Programming C++, C#, JAVA, Python, JS and Lua

Game Engines Unity 3D, Ogre 3D, prior experiences: Unreal, Irrlicht and Gamemaker

Physics Engines PhysX and ODE
V. Control Systems Git, Hg, SVN and CVS

Others Qt, ML-Agents tookit, Visual Studio, Ionic, Cordova, Jenkins, Ejabberd XMPP, Scrum

Game Projects _____

Devikins)

DEVIKINS IS A FREE TO PLAY BLEND OF CLASSIC JRPG STYLE TURN-BASED COMBAT AND CHARACTER BREEDING. SEEK GLORY WITH A GUILD OR CRAFT WEAPONS, EQUIPMENT, AND SKILLS! RAISE YOUR OWN PERSONAL ARMY, AND DEFEAT MONSTERS AND OTHER PLAYERS IN BOTH PVE STORY MODE AND THE PVP ARENA!

Jun. 2021

Vamos Brincar de Banho de Mar (Monica's Gang)

VAMOS BRINCAR DE BANHO DE MAR IS A TOY GAME FROM MONICA'S GANG UNIVERSE. IN IT THE CHILD CAN EXPLORE THE SEA IN 2D, WHICH IS ACTUALLY A BATHTUB, IMAGINE STORIES, ACTIVATE CUTSCENES, EXCHANGE SKINS, FEED CHARACTERS, USE MEANS OF TRANSPORT AND MUCH MORE.

Oct. 2020

Vamos Brincar de Cozinhar (Monica's Gang)

LET'S PLAY COOKING IS A TOY GAME FROM MONICA'S GANG UNIVERSE. IN IT THE CHILD CAN CREATE DIFFERENT RECIPES AND FEED MAGGY. YOU CAN CUT, BAKE, COOK, FRY AND MAKE COOKIES WITH DIFFERENT FOODS

Aug. 2020

BLE - Bomberman Learning Environment

BLE IS BUILT UPON THE ML-AGENT TOOLKIT, DRL, AND IL ALGORITHMS. IT WAS CREATED IN MASTERS DISSERTATION RESEARCH.

May. 2019

Rocket IX

SURVIVAL-STYLE SHIP GAME DEVELOPED USING UNITY3D.

Jul. 2016

Rolimã

ROLLING CART RACING GAME MADE USING THE GAME ENGINE IRRLICHT AND THE PHYSICAL ENGINE ODE AS MAIN ASSESSMENT FOR AN ISOLATED COURSE IN DIGITAL GAMES AT UFMG.

Jun. 2011

Percy Fawcett

2D PUZZLE PLATFORM GAME MADE USING THE GAMEMAKER FRAMEWORK AS ASSESSMENT FOR AN ISOLATED COURSE IN DIGITAL GAMES UFMG.

Mav. 2011

Operação Bauxita

CAR BATTLE GAME DEVELOPED TO TEST THE VISUAL VIRTUAL COMPANY ENGINE.

Jun. 2010

Projeto Pólo

SHOTING GAME DEVELOPED IN C++ AND LUA, USING OGRE GRAPHICS ENGINE, PHYSX PHYSICS ENGINE, OPENAL AUDIO ENGINE AND RAKNET NETWORK ENGINE AS FINAL PROJECT FOR THE GAME DEVELOPMENT COURSE OF PUC-MINAS.

Dec. 2009

RACING GAME DEVELOPED IN XNA AS INTERDISCIPLINARY ASSESSMENT FOR THE GAME DEVELOPMENT COURSE OF PUC-MINAS.

DEVELOPMENT COURSE OF PUC-MINAS.

Batalha Naval: A Neblina

Game developed in C++ using the game engine Irrlicht as interdisciplinary assessment for the Game

Jun. 2008

Dec. 2008

Contratempo

2D PLATFORM GAME DEVELOPED USING THE GAMEMAKER FRAMEWORK AS INTERDISCIPLINARY ASSESSMENT FOR THE GAME DEVELOPMENT COURSE OF PUC-MINAS.

Dec. 2007

Software Projects

AddCement

THE ADDCEMENT SOLUTION ENCOMPASSED THE RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT OF A DIAGNOSTIC PROTOTYPE OF THE CEMENTING STATE ALONG A WELL.

Oct. 2018 - Aug. 2019

Zumpy - Carpooling app

THROUGH ZUMPY, DRIVERS CAN ZERO FUEL EXPENSES AND PASSENGERS CAN COMMUTE BOTH COMFORTABLY AND AFFORDABLY.

Nov. 2013 - Jan. 2017

MineInside

MINEINSIDE IS A WINDOWS PLATFORM PROGRAM USED FOR VISUALIZATION AND MONITORING OF ORE MINES. THERE WERE SEVERAL VERSIONS, AMONG THEM: PLANNING, MONITORING AND RECONSTITUTION.

Mar. 2009 - Oct. 2013

Published Papers

A Visual System for Custom Security Analysis in Cities

Niterói-RJ, Brazil

Co-Author

In 7th Workshop on Visual Analytics, Information Visualization and Scientific Visualization (WVIS) - SIBGRAPI

Learning how to play Bomberman with DeepReinforcement and Imitation Learning

Arequipa, Peru

2019

Co-Autor

Joint International Conference on Entertainment Computing and Serious Games. Springer, Cham, 2019

Honors & Awards

DOMESTIC

2008

2009 **Gold Medal**, Medal of merit in reason of his high grades on his technical degree course.

Best Work, Best interdisciplinary work of the second period of his technical degree course.

PUC-Minas

PUC-Minas